Guide to the Stanford University, Academic Council, Senate Committee on the Relation between the Hoover Institution and the Stanford Professoriate, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Academic Council, Senate Committee on the Relation between the Hoover Institution and the Stanford Professoriate, records
1959-1989
1985-1989
SC0443
Stanford University. Academic Council. Senate Committee on the Relation between the Hoover Institution and the Stanford Professoriate.
1.25 Linear feet
Reports, memoranda, statements, minutes, and background information, 1959-1985; drafts of the Committee's report, with comments, 1985; and post-report correspondence and clippings, 1985-1989. Collection also includes materials pertaining to the Hoover press.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Sanford M. Dornbusch, 1992.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Senate Committee was formed in March 1985 with sociology professor Sanford M. Dornbusch as chair.
Description of the Collection
Reports, memoranda, statements, minutes, and background information, 1959-1985; drafts of the Committee's report, with comments, 1985; and post-report correspondence and clippings, 1985-1989. Collection also includes materials pertaining to the Hoover press.
Access Terms
Dornbusch, Sanford M.; Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace; Stanford University. Academic Council. Senate Committee on the Relation between the Hoover Institution and the Stanford Professoriate.; Hoover Intitute
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Charge to Committee, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees, miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1985 May 6, 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memos (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - News of the Day" - Committee bulletin, 1985 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Press releases, drafts, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - SCRHIP document list (#1-179) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - SCRHIP documents 1-39 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - SCRHIP documents 40-59 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - SCRHIP documents 60-89 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - SCRHIP documents 90-109 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - SCRHIP documents 110-134 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - SCRHIP documents 135-158 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - SCRHIP documents 174-210 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - SCRHIP documents not numbered (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Drafts (Appointments within the Hoover Institution) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Drafts (Collaboration between Depts. and the Hoover Institution) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Drafts (Concerns identified by the Committee) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Drafts (Dept. affiliation for Hoover members) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Drafts (Hoover as a fully independent institution) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Drafts (Introduction) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Drafts (Place of the Hoover Institution in the University structure) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Drafts (Proposals) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Drafts (Report of resource group - the Ward Report) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Drafts (Suggested directions for change) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Drafts, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Draft of report (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Draft of report, with notes, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Draft of report, 1985 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Draft of report, with comments (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Draft of report, with notes (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - de Necochea, Fernando - comments on report, 1985 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Comments on report, 1985 May 17 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Resolution of Academic Council on report of SCRHIP, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Ward Report on Hoover-Stanford appointments, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Notes (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous items (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Post-report file, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Post-report file, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Post-report file, 1987-89, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Duignan, Peter. THE HOOVER INSTITUTION ... SEVENTY-FIVE YEARS OF ITS HISTORY (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, Martin. STANFORD AND HOOVER AND ACADEMIC FREEDOM, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lammi, Walter. file re Hoover Press/1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lammi, Walter. file re Hoover Press/2 (Box 3, Folder 6)